<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>A Humble Programmer</title>
  
  <subtitle>Talk is cheap, show me the code.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2022-07-22T01:07:07.349Z</updated>
  <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>hezhigang</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Little Girl</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/19/Little-Girl-Laura-Elizabeth-Howe-Richards/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/19/Little-Girl-Laura-Elizabeth-Howe-Richards/</id>
    <published>2022-07-20T01:01:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-22T01:07:07.349Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_E._Richards">Laura E. Richards</a></p><p>When Little Girl wakes in the morning gay<br>Then everybody is glad;<br>The cat in the kitchen sits purring away,<br>And the puppy dog barks like mad.<br>The bell in the steeple turns head over heels,<br>That’s his way of showing how glad he feels;<br>And all the wide world seems to say,<br>“Our dear Little Girl is happy to-day!”</p><p>When Little Girl wakes in the morning sad,<br>Then everybody must mourn;<br>The little birds sigh, and the big birds cry,<br>And the scarecrow sobs in the corn.<br>The fishes all pull their hankies out,<br>And go and weep with the poor hornpout,<br>And the clock says, “Tock! I’m sorry to say<br>Our dear Little Girl is sad to-day!”</p><p>So, Little Girl, when you go beddy at night,<br>Put a smile right under your pillow,<br>And when you wake up, just slip it on tight,<br>And wear it all day with a will, oh!<br>Then the sun will shine and the wind will blow,<br>And the bells will ring, “Ho! ho! ho! ho!”<br>For in all the wide world there’s naught can be<br>So sweet as a happy child to see!</p><hr><p><a href="https://americanliterature.com/author/laura-e-richards/poem/little-girl">Little Girl</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laura_E._Richards&quot;&gt;Laura E. Richards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Little Girl wakes in the morning gay&lt;br&gt;Th</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Marie Curie and Henri Poincaré once wrote letters of recommendation for Albert Einstein</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/17/recommendation-letters-for-Albert-Einstein/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/17/recommendation-letters-for-Albert-Einstein/</id>
    <published>2022-07-18T03:26:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-22T01:43:56.471Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script id="MathJax-script" async  src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mathjax@3/es5/tex-mml-chtml.js"></script><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/ba/Curie_and_Poincare_1911_Solvay.jpg/440px-Curie_and_Poincare_1911_Solvay.jpg" alt="Marie Curie and Poincaré talk at the 1911 Solvay Conference"></p><p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henri_Poincar%C3%A9">Henri Poincaré</a>:<br>Nov. 1911</p><p>My dear colleague,</p><p>Mr Einstein is one of the most original thinkers I have ever met. In spite of his youth, he has already achieved a very honourable place among the leading savants of his age. What one has to admire in him above all is <strong>the facility with which he adapts himself to new concepts and knows how to draw from them every possible conclusion</strong>. He has not remained attached to classical principles, and when faced with a problem of physics he is prompt in envisaging all its possibilities. A problem which enters his mind unfolds itself into the anticipation of new phenomena which may one day be verified by experiment. I do not mean to say that all these anticipations will withstand the test of experiment on the day such a test would become possible. Since he seeks in all directions one must, on the contrary, expect most of the trails which he pursues to be blind alleys. <strong>But one must hope at the same time that one of the directions he has indicated may be the right one, and that is enough</strong>. This is indeed how one should proceed. The role of mathematical physics is to ask the right questions, and experiment alone can resolve them.</p><p>The future will show more and more the worth of Mr Einstein, and the university intelligent enough to attract this young master is certain to reap great honour.</p><p>Your most devoted colleague,</p><p>Poincaré</p><hr><p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marie_Curie">Marie Curie</a>:<br>Paris, November 17, 1911</p><p>Dear Sir,</p><p>I have just received your letter, in which you asked for my personal impression of Mr. Einstein, whom I recently had the pleasure to meet. You also say that Mr. Einstein wishes very much to return to Zurich and could soon have the opportunity to do so.</p><p>I have often admired the papers published by Mr. Einstein on issues dealing with modern theoretical physics. Moreover, <strong>I believe that theoretical physicists agree that these papers are of the highest order</strong>. In Brussels, where I participated in a scientific conference in which Mr. Einstein also took part, I was able to appreciate <strong>the clarity of his mind, the extent of his documentation and the depth of his knowledge</strong>. If we consider that Mr. Einstein is still very young, <strong>we are right to have great hope in him, and to see him as one of the leading theoreticians of the future</strong>. I think that the scientific institution willing to give Mr. Einstein the work he desires, either by appointing him an existing chair or by creating for him the chair in the conditions he deserves, could be greatly honored by such a decision and would certainly be providing a great service to science.</p><p>If, by offering my opinion, I could by a small measure contribute to the solution desired by Mr. Einstein, I would be extremely pleased.</p><p>Accept, I beg of you, dear Sir, the assurance of my best wishes.</p><p>M. Curie</p><p>Faculty of Sciences, Paris<br>(General Physics Laboratory)</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://theuijunkie.com/einstein-marie-curie-letter-recommendation/">The Time Albert Einstein Asked Marie Curie A Letter Of Recommendation To Secure A Job</a></li><li>Henri Poincaré is often described as a polymath, and in mathematics as “<strong>The Last Universalist</strong>“, since he excelled in all fields of the discipline as it existed during his lifetime.</li><li>When <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bertrand_Russell">Bertrand Russell</a> was asked by a French politician who he thought the greatest man France had produced, he replied without hesitation, “Poincaré”. The politician was surprised that he’d chosen the prime minister <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raymond_Poincar%C3%A9">Raymond Poincaré</a> above the likes of Napoleon, Balzac. Russell replied, “I don’t mean Raymond Poincare but his cousin, “the mathematician, Henri Poincaré.”</li><li>Poincaré’s fame was so great, in fact, that just after World War I when the English philosopher Bertrand Russell was asked who was the greatest Frenchman of modern times he answered, “Poincaré,” without hesitation. Thinking he was referring to Raymond, Henri’s cousin who had become president of France, the questioner frowned. “No, not that Poincaré,” Russell said quickly. “Henri Poincaré”.</li><li>Isaac Newton and Albert Einstein are among the scientists who experienced their own <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annus_mirabilis">annus mirabilis</a>, a miraculous year of breakthroughs.</li><li>1666 — The year of wonders: In 1666 Isaac Newton, aged 23, made revolutionary inventions and discoveries in calculus, motion, optics and gravitation. It was in this year that Newton was alleged to have observed an apple falling from a tree, and in which he in any case hit upon the law of universal gravitation (Newton’s apple). He was afforded the time to work on his theories due to the closure of Cambridge University by an outbreak of plague.</li><li>Newton is not the only scientist said to have experienced a miraculous year of breakthroughs. Albert Einstein was 26 years old in 1905, when—while working as a patent office clerk in Bern, Switzerland, a job that he later said gave him time for thought experiments—he published four papers of major significance in the journal Annalen der Physik. They dealt with space, time, mass, and energy, topics that were central to the foundations of modern physics.</li><li>1905 — Albert Einstein: It was in this year that Albert Einstein, aged 26, published important discoveries concerning the photoelectric effect, Brownian motion, the special theory of relativity, and the famous \(E = mc^2\) equation. His four articles, collectively known as his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annus_mirabilis_papers">Annus Mirabilis papers</a>, were published in Annalen der Physik in 1905.</li><li><a href="https://www.americanscientist.org/article/annus-mirabilis">Annus Mirabilis</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;script id=&quot;MathJax-script&quot; async
  src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mathjax@3/es5/tex-mml-chtml.js&quot;&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://uploa</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Quantum hype</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/12/Quantum-hype-VSI-John-Polkinghorne/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/12/Quantum-hype-VSI-John-Polkinghorne/</id>
    <published>2022-07-13T03:54:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-14T20:20:30.078Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Polkinghorne">John Polkinghorne</a></p><p>It seems appropriate to close this chapter with an intellectual health warning. Quantum theory is certainly strange and surprising, but it is not so odd that according to it ‘anything goes’. Of course, no one would actually argue with such crudity, but there is a kind of discourse that can come perilously close to adopting that caricature attitude. One might call it ‘quantum hype’. I want to suggest that sobriety is in order when making an appeal to quantum insight.</p><p>We have seen that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EPR_paradox">EPR</a> effect does not offer an explanation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telepathy">telepathy</a>, for its degree of mutual <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_entanglement">entanglement</a> is not one that could facilitate the transfer of information. Quantum processes in the brain may possibly have some connection with the existence of the human conscious mind, but random subatomic uncertainty is very different indeed form the exercise of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_will">free will</a> of an agent. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave%E2%80%93particle_duality">Wave/particle duality</a> is a highly surprising and instructive phenomenon, whose seemingly paradoxical character has been resolved for us by the insights of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_field_theory">quantum field theory</a>. It does not, however, afford us a licence to indulge in embracing any pair of apparently contradictory notions that take our fancy. Like a powerful drug, quantum theory is wonderful when applied correctly, disastrous when abused and misapplied.</p><p>&copy; excerpted from <a href="https://www.veryshortintroductions.com/view/10.1093/actrade/9780192802521.001.0001/actrade-9780192802521">Quantum Theory: A Very Short Introduction</a>, chapter 6 Lessons and meanings</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Polkinghorne&quot;&gt;John Polkinghorne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems appropriate to close this chapter with</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>LeetCode SQL Questions</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/04/leetcode-sql-questions/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/04/leetcode-sql-questions/</id>
    <published>2022-07-05T03:53:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-06T15:49:09.076Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="511-Game-Play-Analysis-I"><a href="#511-Game-Play-Analysis-I" class="headerlink" title="511. Game Play Analysis I"></a>511. Game Play Analysis I</h1><p><a href="https://leetcode.com/problems/game-play-analysis-i/">511. Game Play Analysis I</a></p><h2 id="Transact-SQL"><a href="#Transact-SQL" class="headerlink" title="Transact-SQL"></a>Transact-SQL</h2><figure class="highlight sql"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="keyword">SELECT</span> player_id <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;player_id&#x27;</span>, <span class="built_in">MIN</span>(event_date) <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;first_login&#x27;</span> </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">FROM</span> Activity </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">GROUP</span> <span class="keyword">BY</span> player_id</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="Submission-Detail"><a href="#Submission-Detail" class="headerlink" title="Submission Detail"></a>Submission Detail</h3><ul><li>12 / 12 test cases passed.</li><li>Runtime: 2929 ms, faster than 51.13% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Game Play Analysis I.</li><li>Memory Usage: 0B, less than 100.00% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Game Play Analysis I.</li></ul><h1 id="584-Find-Customer-Referee"><a href="#584-Find-Customer-Referee" class="headerlink" title="584. Find Customer Referee"></a>584. Find Customer Referee</h1><p><a href="https://leetcode.com/problems/find-customer-referee/">584. Find Customer Referee</a></p><h2 id="Transact-SQL-1"><a href="#Transact-SQL-1" class="headerlink" title="Transact-SQL"></a>Transact-SQL</h2><figure class="highlight sql"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="keyword">SELECT</span> CU.name <span class="keyword">FROM</span> Customer <span class="keyword">AS</span> CU </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">WHERE</span> CU.referee_id <span class="keyword">is</span> <span class="keyword">null</span> <span class="keyword">OR</span> CU.referee_id <span class="operator">&lt;&gt;</span> <span class="number">2</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="Submission-Detail-1"><a href="#Submission-Detail-1" class="headerlink" title="Submission Detail"></a>Submission Detail</h3><ul><li>19 / 19 test cases passed.</li><li>Runtime: 972 ms, faster than 63.09% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Find Customer Referee.</li><li>Memory Usage: 0B, less than 100.00% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Find Customer Referee.</li></ul><h1 id="586-Customer-Placing-the-Largest-Number-of-Orders"><a href="#586-Customer-Placing-the-Largest-Number-of-Orders" class="headerlink" title="586. Customer Placing the Largest Number of Orders"></a>586. Customer Placing the Largest Number of Orders</h1><p><a href="https://leetcode.com/problems/customer-placing-the-largest-number-of-orders/">586. Customer Placing the Largest Number of Orders</a></p><h2 id="Transact-SQL-2"><a href="#Transact-SQL-2" class="headerlink" title="Transact-SQL"></a>Transact-SQL</h2><figure class="highlight sql"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="keyword">SELECT</span> TOP <span class="number">1</span> V.customer_number <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;customer_number&#x27;</span> <span class="keyword">FROM</span> </span><br><span class="line">(</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">SELECT</span> O.customer_number <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;customer_number&#x27;</span>, <span class="built_in">COUNT</span>(O.order_number) <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;num&#x27;</span> </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">FROM</span> Orders <span class="keyword">AS</span> O </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">GROUP</span> <span class="keyword">BY</span> O.customer_number</span><br><span class="line">) <span class="keyword">AS</span> V </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">ORDER</span> <span class="keyword">BY</span> V.num <span class="keyword">DESC</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="Submission-Detail-2"><a href="#Submission-Detail-2" class="headerlink" title="Submission Detail"></a>Submission Detail</h3><ul><li>20 / 20 test cases passed.</li><li>Runtime: 779 ms, faster than 90.16% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Customer Placing the Largest Number of Orders.</li><li>Memory Usage: 0B, less than 100.00% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Customer Placing the Largest Number of Orders.</li></ul><h1 id="607-Sales-Person"><a href="#607-Sales-Person" class="headerlink" title="607. Sales Person"></a>607. Sales Person</h1><p><a href="https://leetcode.com/problems/sales-person/">607. Sales Person</a></p><h2 id="Transact-SQL-3"><a href="#Transact-SQL-3" class="headerlink" title="Transact-SQL"></a>Transact-SQL</h2><h3 id="1"><a href="#1" class="headerlink" title="1"></a>1</h3><figure class="highlight sql"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="keyword">SELECT</span> SP.name <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;name&#x27;</span> <span class="keyword">FROM</span> SalesPerson <span class="keyword">AS</span> SP </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">WHERE</span> SP.sales_id <span class="keyword">NOT</span> <span class="keyword">IN</span> </span><br><span class="line">(</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">SELECT</span> O.sales_id <span class="keyword">FROM</span> Company <span class="keyword">AS</span> C </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">JOIN</span> Orders <span class="keyword">AS</span> O <span class="keyword">ON</span> O.com_id <span class="operator">=</span> C.com_id </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">WHERE</span> C.name <span class="operator">=</span> <span class="string">&#x27;RED&#x27;</span></span><br><span class="line">)</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h4 id="Submission-Detail-3"><a href="#Submission-Detail-3" class="headerlink" title="Submission Detail"></a>Submission Detail</h4><ul><li>20 / 20 test cases passed.</li><li>Runtime: 2418 ms, faster than 5.03% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Sales Person.</li><li>Memory Usage: 0B, less than 100.00% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Sales Person.</li></ul><h3 id="2"><a href="#2" class="headerlink" title="2"></a>2</h3><figure class="highlight sql"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="keyword">SELECT</span> SP.name <span class="keyword">AS</span> <span class="string">&#x27;name&#x27;</span> <span class="keyword">FROM</span> SalesPerson <span class="keyword">AS</span> SP </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">LEFT</span> <span class="keyword">OUTER</span> <span class="keyword">JOIN</span> </span><br><span class="line">(</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">SELECT</span> O.sales_id, O.order_id <span class="keyword">FROM</span> Company <span class="keyword">AS</span> C </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">JOIN</span> Orders <span class="keyword">AS</span> O <span class="keyword">ON</span> O.com_id <span class="operator">=</span> C.com_id </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">WHERE</span> C.name <span class="operator">=</span> <span class="string">&#x27;RED&#x27;</span></span><br><span class="line">) <span class="keyword">AS</span> V </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">ON</span> SP.sales_id <span class="operator">=</span> V.sales_id </span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">WHERE</span> V.order_id <span class="keyword">IS</span> <span class="keyword">NULL</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h4 id="Submission-Detail-4"><a href="#Submission-Detail-4" class="headerlink" title="Submission Detail"></a>Submission Detail</h4><ul><li>20 / 20 test cases passed.</li><li>Runtime: 859 ms, faster than 96.62% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Sales Person.</li><li>Memory Usage: 0B, less than 100.00% of MS SQL Server online submissions for Sales Person.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;511-Game-Play-Analysis-I&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#511-Game-Play-Analysis-I&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;511. Game Play Analysis I&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;511. Game Pla</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="LeetCode" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/LeetCode/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My English Words List - July - 2022</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/02/My-English-Words-List-July-2022/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/02/My-English-Words-List-July-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-07-02T17:37:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-30T22:15:53.061Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="drone"><a href="#drone" class="headerlink" title="drone"></a>drone</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/drone">drone</a></p><h2 id="noun"><a href="#noun" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5d/Intel-Drone-100-Light-Show-980x653.jpg/440px-Intel-Drone-100-Light-Show-980x653.jpg" alt="&quot;Drone100&quot; performed by Ars Electronica Futurelab, for Intel, in 2015"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drone_art">Drone art</a></p><p>Drone art &#40;also known as drone display or drone light show&#41; is the use of multiple unmanned aerial vehicles &#40;drones&#41;, often quadcopters, flying in a coordinated fashion with light fixtures attached. They are usually equipped with multiple LEDs, and the display held at night. The first drone display was presented in 2012 in Linz/Austria, where the Ars Electronica Futurelab introduced SPAXELS &#40;short for “space elements”&#41; for the first time.</p><h1 id="hazard"><a href="#hazard" class="headerlink" title="hazard"></a>hazard</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/hazard">hazard</a></p><h2 id="noun-1"><a href="#noun-1" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>hazards on the roadway</p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e2/A19_Hazard_warning.svg/150px-A19_Hazard_warning.svg.png" alt="ISO symbol for hazard warning signal"></p><p>hazard lights</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hazard">Hazard</a></p><h1 id="outage"><a href="#outage" class="headerlink" title="outage"></a>outage</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/outage">outage</a></p><h2 id="noun-2"><a href="#noun-2" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>The fallout from a massive network <strong>outage</strong> at Rogers Communications that shut down mobile and internet services across much of Canada</p><p>a daylong <strong>outage</strong> at the telecom giant that left millions of Canadians without internet and cellular service</p><h1 id="meme"><a href="#meme" class="headerlink" title="meme"></a>meme</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/meme">meme</a></p><h2 id="noun-3"><a href="#noun-3" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><ul><li>an amusing or interesting item (such as a captioned picture or video) or genre of items that is spread widely online especially through social media</li><li>an idea, behavior, style, or usage that spreads from person to person within a culture</li></ul><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meme">Meme</a></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Dawkins">Richard Dawkins</a> coined the word meme in his 1976 book <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Selfish_Gene">The Selfish Gene</a></p><h1 id="warrior"><a href="#warrior" class="headerlink" title="warrior"></a>warrior</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/warrior">warrior</a></p><h2 id="noun-4"><a href="#noun-4" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2d/Mounted_Mongol_warrior_recreation.jpg/602px-Mounted_Mongol_warrior_recreation.jpg" alt="Recreation of a mounted warrior from the Mongol Empire."></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warrior">Warrior</a></p><h1 id="dexterity"><a href="#dexterity" class="headerlink" title="dexterity"></a>dexterity</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/dexterity">dexterity</a></p><h2 id="noun-5"><a href="#noun-5" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fine_motor_skill">Fine motor skill</a></p><p>Fine motor skill &#40; or dexterity &#41; is the coordination of small muscles in movement with the eyes, hands and fingers. The complex levels of manual dexterity that humans exhibit can be related to the nervous system. Fine motor skills aid in the growth of intelligence and develop continuously throughout the stages of human development.</p><h1 id="armor"><a href="#armor" class="headerlink" title="armor"></a>armor</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/armor">armor</a></p><h2 id="noun-6"><a href="#noun-6" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e3/Rustning%2C_Gustav_Vasa_-_Livrustkammaren_-_32921.tif/lossy-page1-360px-Rustning%2C_Gustav_Vasa_-_Livrustkammaren_-_32921.tif.jpg" alt="Plate armour"></p><p><img src="https://merriam-webster.com/assets/mw/static/art/dict/armor.gif" alt="armor"></p><p>A turtle’s shell is its armor.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armour">Armour</a></p><h1 id="polymorphism"><a href="#polymorphism" class="headerlink" title="polymorphism"></a>polymorphism</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/polymorphic">polymorphism</a></p><h2 id="noun-7"><a href="#noun-7" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymorphism_%28computer_science%29">Polymorphism &#40;computer science&#41;</a></p><h1 id="commentary"><a href="#commentary" class="headerlink" title="commentary"></a>commentary</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/commentary">commentary</a></p><h2 id="noun-8"><a href="#noun-8" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>Blackstone’s Commentaries on the Laws of England</p><p>Caesar’s Commentaries on the Gallic War</p><p>a commentary on Dante’s Divine Comedy</p><p>The magazine article is a commentary on cyberbullying.</p><p>The book is a commentary on her experiences abroad.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commentary">Commentary</a></p><h1 id="heal"><a href="#heal" class="headerlink" title="heal"></a>heal</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/heal">heal</a></p><h2 id="verb"><a href="#verb" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><ul><li>to make or become healthy or well again</li></ul><p>The cut healed slowly.</p><p>heal the sick</p><h1 id="assassin"><a href="#assassin" class="headerlink" title="assassin"></a>assassin</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/assassin">assassin</a></p><h2 id="noun-9"><a href="#noun-9" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>John Wilkes Booth was the assassin of Abraham Lincoln.</p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/37/Lincoln_assassination_slide_c1900_-_Restoration.jpg/440px-Lincoln_assassination_slide_c1900_-_Restoration.jpg" alt="Shown in the presidential booth of Ford&#39;s Theatre, from left to right, are assassin John Wilkes Booth, Abraham Lincoln, Mary Todd Lincoln, Clara Harris and Henry Rathbone"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assassination">Assassination</a></p><h1 id="concatenation"><a href="#concatenation" class="headerlink" title="concatenation"></a>concatenation</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/concatenation">concatenation</a></p><h2 id="noun-10"><a href="#noun-10" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>“Hello, “ &#43; “World” has the value “Hello, World”. </p><p>The &#43; operator can be used between strings to combine them. This is called concatenation.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concatenation">Concatenation</a></p><h1 id="trunk"><a href="#trunk" class="headerlink" title="trunk"></a>trunk</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/trunk">trunk</a></p><h2 id="noun-11"><a href="#noun-11" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/67/2010_Porsche_Boxster_Spyder_%285217139071%29.jpg/440px-2010_Porsche_Boxster_Spyder_%285217139071%29.jpg" alt="The open trunk in the rear of a Porsche Boxster"></p><ul><li>the enclosed space in the rear of an automobile for carrying articles</li><li>the main body of an anatomical part (as a nerve or blood vessel) that divides into branches</li></ul><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trunk_%28car%29">Trunk &#40;car&#41;</a></p><h1 id="tease"><a href="#tease" class="headerlink" title="tease"></a>tease</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/tease">tease</a></p><h2 id="verb-1"><a href="#verb-1" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><p>He and his wife enjoy teasing each other about their different tastes in music. </p><p>He was always teased by his brother about being short.</p><p>some kids tease me about my name.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teasing">Teasing</a></p><h1 id="traction"><a href="#traction" class="headerlink" title="traction"></a>traction</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/traction">traction</a></p><h2 id="noun-12"><a href="#noun-12" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>These tires get good traction on wet roads.</p><p>The wheels get more traction when the road is dry.</p><p>the traction of a wheel on a rail</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Traction_%28engineering%29">Traction &#40;engineering&#41;</a></p><h1 id="throne"><a href="#throne" class="headerlink" title="throne"></a>throne</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/throne">throne</a></p><h2 id="noun-13"><a href="#noun-13" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/75/Inside_the_Forbidden_City.jpg/280px-Inside_the_Forbidden_City.jpg" alt="The Dragon Throne of the Emperor of China in the Forbidden City in Beijing."></p><p>The king sat on his throne.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Throne">Throne</a></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_of_Thrones">Game of Thrones</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;drone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#drone&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;drone&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;drone&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/drone&quot;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="ELL" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/ELL/"/>
    
    <category term="English" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/English/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Canada</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/01/Canada-Billy-Collins/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/07/01/Canada-Billy-Collins/</id>
    <published>2022-07-01T04:21:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-01T04:25:51.721Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billy_Collins">Billy Collins</a></p><p>I am writing this on a strip of white birch bark<br>that I cut from a tree with a penknife.<br>There is no other way to express adequately<br>the immensity of the clouds that are passing over the farms<br>and wooded lakes of Ontario and the endless visibility<br>that hands you the horizon on a platter.</p><p>I am also writing this in a wooden canoe,<br>a point of balance in the middle of Lake Couchiching,<br>resting the birch bark against my knees.<br>I can feel the sun’s hands on my bare back,<br>but I am thinking of winter,<br>snow piled up in all the provinces<br>and the solemnity of the long grain-ships<br>that pass the cold months moored at Owen Sound.</p><p>O Canada, as the anthem goes,<br>scene of my boyhood summers,<br>you are the pack of Sweet Caporals on the table,<br>you are the dove-soft train whistle in the night,<br>you are the empty chair at the end of an empty dock.<br>You are the shelves of books in a lakeside cottage:<br>Gift from the Sea by Anne Morrow Lindbergh,<br>A Child’s Garden of Verses by Robert Louis Stevenson,<br>Anne of Avonlea by L. M. Montgomery,<br>So You’re Going to Paris! by Clara E. Laughlin,<br>and Peril Over the Airport, one<br>of the Vicky Barr Flight Stewardess series<br>by Helen Wills whom some will remember<br>as the author of the Cherry Ames Nurse stories.<br>What has become of the languorous girls<br>who would pass the long limp summer evenings reading<br>Cherry Ames, Student Nurse, Cherry Ames, Senior Nurse,<br>Cherry Ames, Chief Nurse, and Cherry Ames, Flight Nurse?<br>Where are they now, the ones who shared her adventures<br>as a veterans’ nurse, private duty nurse, visiting nurse,<br>cruise nurse, night supervisor, mountaineer nurse,<br>dude ranch nurse (there is little she has not done),<br>rest home nurse, department store nurse,<br>boarding school nurse, and country doctor’s nurse?</p><p>O Canada, I have not forgotten you,<br>and as I kneel in my canoe, beholding this vision<br>of a bookcase, I pray that I remain in your vast,<br>polar, North American memory.<br>You are the paddle, the snowshoe, the cabin in the pines.<br>You are Jean de Brébeuf with his martyr’s necklace of hatchet heads.<br>You are the moose in the clearing and the moosehead on the wall.<br>You are the rapids, the propeller, the kerosene lamp.<br>You are the dust that coats the roadside berries.<br>But not only that.<br>You are the two boys with pails walking along that road,<br>and one of them, the taller one minus the straw hat, is me.</p><hr><p><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/46705/canada-56d226acee378">Canada</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billy_Collins&quot;&gt;Billy Collins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this on a strip of white birch bark&lt;br&gt;tha</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>An Essay on Criticism Part 3</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/30/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-3-Alexander-Pope/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/30/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-3-Alexander-Pope/</id>
    <published>2022-06-30T15:26:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-01T02:29:19.324Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope">Alexander Pope</a></p><p>Learn then what morals critics ought to show,<br>For ‘tis but half a judge’s task, to know.<br>‘Tis not enough, taste, judgment, learning, join;<br>In all you speak, let truth and candour shine:<br>That not alone what to your sense is due,<br>All may allow; but seek your friendship too.</p><p>Be silent always when you doubt your sense;<br>And speak, though sure, with seeming diffidence:<br>Some positive, persisting fops we know,<br>Who, if once wrong, will needs be always so;<br>But you, with pleasure own your errors past,<br>And make each day a critic on the last.</p><p>‘Tis not enough, your counsel still be true;<br>Blunt truths more mischief than nice falsehoods do;<br>Men must be taught as if you taught them not;<br>And things unknown proposed as things forgot.<br>Without good breeding, truth is disapprov’d;<br>That only makes superior sense belov’d.</p><p>Be niggards of advice on no pretence;<br>For the worst avarice is that of sense.<br>With mean complacence ne’er betray your trust,<br>Nor be so civil as to prove unjust.<br>Fear not the anger of the wise to raise;<br>Those best can bear reproof, who merit praise.</p><p>‘Twere well might critics still this freedom take,<br>But Appius reddens at each word you speak,<br>And stares, Tremendous ! with a threatening eye,<br>Like some fierce tyrant in old tapestry!<br>Fear most to tax an honourable fool,<br>Whose right it is, uncensur’d, to be dull;<br>Such, without wit, are poets when they please,<br>As without learning they can take degrees.<br>Leave dangerous truths to unsuccessful satires,<br>And flattery to fulsome dedicators,<br>Whom, when they praise, the world believes no more,<br>Than when they promise to give scribbling o’er.<br>‘Tis best sometimes your censure to restrain,<br>And charitably let the dull be vain:<br>Your silence there is better than your spite,<br>For who can rail so long as they can write?<br>Still humming on, their drowsy course they keep,<br>And lash’d so long, like tops, are lash’d asleep.<br>False steps but help them to renew the race,<br>As after stumbling, jades will mend their pace.<br>What crowds of these, impenitently bold,<br>In sounds and jingling syllables grown old,<br>Still run on poets, in a raging vein,<br>Even to the dregs and squeezings of the brain,<br>Strain out the last, dull droppings of their sense,<br>And rhyme with all the rage of impotence!</p><p>Such shameless bards we have; and yet ‘tis true,<br>There are as mad, abandon’d critics too.<br>The bookful blockhead, ignorantly read,<br>With loads of learned lumber in his head,<br>With his own tongue still edifies his ears,<br>And always list’ning to himself appears.<br>All books he reads, and all he reads assails,<br>From Dryden’s Fables down to Durfey’s Tales.<br>With him, most authors steal their works, or buy;<br>Garth did not write his own Dispensary .<br>Name a new play, and he’s the poet’s friend,<br>Nay show’d his faults—but when would poets mend?<br>No place so sacred from such fops is barr’d,<br>Nor is Paul’s church more safe than Paul’s churchyard:<br>Nay, fly to altars; there they’ll talk you dead:</p><blockquote><p>For fools rush in where angels fear to tread.</p></blockquote><p>Distrustful sense with modest caution speaks;<br>It still looks home, and short excursions makes;<br>But rattling nonsense in full volleys breaks;<br>And never shock’d, and never turn’d aside,<br>Bursts out, resistless, with a thund’ring tide.</p><p>But where’s the man, who counsel can bestow,<br>Still pleas’d to teach, and yet not proud to know?<br>Unbias’d, or by favour or by spite;<br>Not dully prepossess’d, nor blindly right;<br>Though learn’d, well-bred; and though well-bred, sincere;<br>Modestly bold, and humanly severe?<br>Who to a friend his faults can freely show,<br>And gladly praise the merit of a foe?<br>Blest with a taste exact, yet unconfin’d;<br>A knowledge both of books and human kind;<br>Gen’rous converse; a soul exempt from pride;<br>And love to praise, with reason on his side?</p><p>Such once were critics; such the happy few,<br>Athens and Rome in better ages knew.<br>The mighty Stagirite first left the shore,<br>Spread all his sails, and durst the deeps explore:<br>He steer’d securely, and discover’d far,<br>Led by the light of the Mæonian Star.<br>Poets, a race long unconfin’d and free,<br>Still fond and proud of savage liberty,<br>Receiv’d his laws; and stood convinc’d ‘twas fit,<br>Who conquer’d nature, should preside o’er wit.</p><p>Horace still charms with graceful negligence,<br>And without methods talks us into sense,<br>Will, like a friend, familiarly convey<br>The truest notions in the easiest way.<br>He, who supreme in judgment, as in wit,<br>Might boldly censure, as he boldly writ,<br>Yet judg’d with coolness, though he sung with fire;<br>His precepts teach but what his works inspire.<br>Our critics take a contrary extreme,<br>They judge with fury, but they write with fle’me:<br>Nor suffers Horace more in wrong translations<br>By wits, than critics in as wrong quotations.</p><p>See Dionysius Homer’s thoughts refine,<br>And call new beauties forth from ev’ry line!<br>Fancy and art in gay Petronius please,<br>The scholar’s learning, with the courtier’s ease.</p><p>In grave Quintilian’s copious work we find<br>The justest rules, and clearest method join’d;<br>Thus useful arms in magazines we place,<br>All rang’d in order, and dispos’d with grace,<br>But less to please the eye, than arm the hand,<br>Still fit for use, and ready at command.</p><p>Thee, bold Longinus! all the Nine inspire,<br>And bless their critic with a poet’s fire.<br>An ardent judge, who zealous in his trust,<br>With warmth gives sentence, yet is always just;<br>Whose own example strengthens all his laws;<br>And is himself that great sublime he draws.</p><p>Thus long succeeding critics justly reign’d,<br>Licence repress’d, and useful laws ordain’d;<br>Learning and Rome alike in empire grew,<br>And arts still follow’d where her eagles flew;<br>From the same foes, at last, both felt their doom,<br>And the same age saw learning fall, and Rome.<br>With tyranny, then superstition join’d,<br>As that the body, this enslav’d the mind;<br>Much was believ’d, but little understood,<br>And to be dull was constru’d to be good;<br>A second deluge learning thus o’er-run,<br>And the monks finish’d what the Goths begun.</p><p>At length Erasmus, that great, injur’d name,<br>(The glory of the priesthood, and the shame!)<br>Stemm’d the wild torrent of a barb’rous age,<br>And drove those holy Vandals off the stage.</p><p>But see! each Muse, in Leo’s golden days,<br>Starts from her trance, and trims her wither’d bays!<br>Rome’s ancient genius, o’er its ruins spread,<br>Shakes off the dust, and rears his rev’rend head!<br>Then sculpture and her sister-arts revive;<br>Stones leap’d to form, and rocks began to live;<br>With sweeter notes each rising temple rung;<br>A Raphael painted, and a Vida sung.<br>Immortal Vida! on whose honour’d brow<br>The poet’s bays and critic’s ivy grow:<br>Cremona now shall ever boast thy name,<br>As next in place to Mantua, next in fame!</p><p>But soon by impious arms from Latium chas’d,<br>Their ancient bounds the banished Muses pass’d;<br>Thence arts o’er all the northern world advance;<br>But critic-learning flourish’d most in France.<br>The rules a nation born to serve, obeys,<br>And Boileau still in right of Horace sways.<br>But we, brave Britons, foreign laws despis’d,<br>And kept unconquer’d, and uncivilis’d,<br>Fierce for the liberties of wit, and bold,<br>We still defied the Romans, as of old.<br>Yet some there were, among the sounder few<br>Of those who less presum’d, and better knew,<br>Who durst assert the juster ancient cause,<br>And here restor’d wit’s fundamental laws.<br>Such was the Muse, whose rules and practice tell<br>“Nature’s chief master-piece is writing well.”<br>Such was Roscommon—not more learn’d than good,<br>With manners gen’rous as his noble blood;<br>To him the wit of Greece and Rome was known,<br>And ev’ry author’s merit, but his own.<br>Such late was Walsh—the Muse’s judge and friend,<br>Who justly knew to blame or to commend;<br>To failings mild, but zealous for desert;<br>The clearest head, and the sincerest heart.<br>This humble praise, lamented shade! receive,<br>This praise at least a grateful Muse may give:<br>The Muse, whose early voice you taught to sing,<br>Prescrib’d her heights, and prun’d her tender wing,<br>(Her guide now lost) no more attempts to rise,<br>But in low numbers short excursions tries:<br>Content, if hence th’ unlearn’d their wants may view,<br>The learn’d reflect on what before they knew:<br>Careless of censure, nor too fond of fame,<br>Still pleas’d to praise, yet not afraid to blame,<br>Averse alike to flatter, or offend,<br>Not free from faults, nor yet too vain to mend.</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/44898/an-essay-on-criticism-part-3">An Essay on Criticism: Part 3</a></li><li>fools rush in where angels fear to tread 傻瓜唐突造次，贤人明智慎行</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope&quot;&gt;Alexander Pope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn then what morals critics ought to show,&lt;br&gt;For </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>An Essay on Criticism Part 2</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/29/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-2-Alexander-Pope/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/29/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-2-Alexander-Pope/</id>
    <published>2022-06-29T19:03:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-30T03:16:04.346Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope">Alexander Pope</a></p><p>Of all the causes which conspire to blind<br>Man’s erring judgment, and misguide the mind,<br>What the weak head with strongest bias rules,<br>Is pride, the never-failing vice of fools.<br>Whatever Nature has in worth denied,<br>She gives in large recruits of needful pride;<br>For as in bodies, thus in souls, we find<br>What wants in blood and spirits, swell’d with wind;<br>Pride, where wit fails, steps in to our defence,<br>And fills up all the mighty void of sense!<br>If once right reason drives that cloud away,<br>Truth breaks upon us with resistless day;<br>Trust not yourself; but your defects to know,<br>Make use of ev’ry friend—and ev’ry foe.</p><blockquote><p>A little learning is a dang’rous thing;<br>Drink deep, or taste not the Pierian spring:</p></blockquote><p>There shallow draughts intoxicate the brain,<br>And drinking largely sobers us again.<br>Fir’d at first sight with what the Muse imparts,<br>In fearless youth we tempt the heights of arts,<br>While from the bounded level of our mind,<br>Short views we take, nor see the lengths behind,<br>But more advanc’d, behold with strange surprise<br>New, distant scenes of endless science rise!<br>So pleas’d at first, the tow’ring Alps we try,<br>Mount o’er the vales, and seem to tread the sky;<br>Th’ eternal snows appear already past,<br>And the first clouds and mountains seem the last;<br>But those attain’d, we tremble to survey<br>The growing labours of the lengthen’d way,<br>Th’ increasing prospect tires our wand’ring eyes,<br>Hills peep o’er hills, and Alps on Alps arise!</p><p>A perfect judge will read each work of wit<br>With the same spirit that its author writ,<br>Survey the whole, nor seek slight faults to find,<br>Where nature moves, and rapture warms the mind;<br>Nor lose, for that malignant dull delight,<br>The gen’rous pleasure to be charm’d with wit.<br>But in such lays as neither ebb, nor flow,<br>Correctly cold, and regularly low,<br>That shunning faults, one quiet tenour keep;<br>We cannot blame indeed—but we may sleep.<br>In wit, as nature, what affects our hearts<br>Is not th’ exactness of peculiar parts;<br>‘Tis not a lip, or eye, we beauty call,<br>But the joint force and full result of all.<br>Thus when we view some well-proportion’d dome,<br>(The world’s just wonder, and ev’n thine, O Rome!’<br>No single parts unequally surprise;<br>All comes united to th’ admiring eyes;<br>No monstrous height, or breadth, or length appear;<br>The whole at once is bold, and regular.</p><p>Whoever thinks a faultless piece to see,<br>Thinks what ne’er was, nor is, nor e’er shall be.<br>In ev’ry work regard the writer’s end,<br>Since none can compass more than they intend;<br>And if the means be just, the conduct true,<br>Applause, in spite of trivial faults, is due.<br>As men of breeding, sometimes men of wit,<br>T’ avoid great errors, must the less commit:<br>Neglect the rules each verbal critic lays,<br>For not to know such trifles, is a praise.<br>Most critics, fond of some subservient art,<br>Still make the whole depend upon a part:<br>They talk of principles, but notions prize,<br>And all to one lov’d folly sacrifice.</p><p>Once on a time, La Mancha’s knight, they say,<br>A certain bard encount’ring on the way,<br>Discours’d in terms as just, with looks as sage,<br>As e’er could Dennis of the Grecian stage;<br>Concluding all were desp’rate sots and fools,<br>Who durst depart from Aristotle’s rules.<br>Our author, happy in a judge so nice,<br>Produc’d his play, and begg’d the knight’s advice,<br>Made him observe the subject and the plot,<br>The manners, passions, unities, what not?<br>All which, exact to rule, were brought about,<br>Were but a combat in the lists left out.<br>“What! leave the combat out?” exclaims the knight;<br>“Yes, or we must renounce the Stagirite.”<br>“Not so by Heav’n” (he answers in a rage)<br>“Knights, squires, and steeds, must enter on the stage.”<br>So vast a throng the stage can ne’er contain.<br>“Then build a new, or act it in a plain.”</p><p>Thus critics, of less judgment than caprice,<br>Curious not knowing, not exact but nice,<br>Form short ideas; and offend in arts<br>(As most in manners) by a love to parts.</p><p>Some to conceit alone their taste confine,<br>And glitt’ring thoughts struck out at ev’ry line;<br>Pleas’d with a work where nothing’s just or fit;<br>One glaring chaos and wild heap of wit.<br>Poets, like painters, thus, unskill’d to trace<br>The naked nature and the living grace,<br>With gold and jewels cover ev’ry part,<br>And hide with ornaments their want of art.<br>True wit is nature to advantage dress’d,<br>What oft was thought, but ne’er so well express’d,<br>Something, whose truth convinc’d at sight we find,<br>That gives us back the image of our mind.<br>As shades more sweetly recommend the light,<br>So modest plainness sets off sprightly wit.<br>For works may have more wit than does ‘em good,<br>As bodies perish through excess of blood.</p><p>Others for language all their care express,<br>And value books, as women men, for dress:<br>Their praise is still—“the style is excellent”:<br>The sense, they humbly take upon content.<br>Words are like leaves; and where they most abound,<br>Much fruit of sense beneath is rarely found.<br>False eloquence, like the prismatic glass,<br>Its gaudy colours spreads on ev’ry place;<br>The face of Nature we no more survey,<br>All glares alike, without distinction gay:<br>But true expression, like th’ unchanging sun,<br>Clears, and improves whate’er it shines upon,<br>It gilds all objects, but it alters none.<br>Expression is the dress of thought, and still<br>Appears more decent, as more suitable;<br>A vile conceit in pompous words express’d,<br>Is like a clown in regal purple dress’d:<br>For diff’rent styles with diff’rent subjects sort,<br>As several garbs with country, town, and court.<br>Some by old words to fame have made pretence,<br>Ancients in phrase, mere moderns in their sense;<br>Such labour’d nothings, in so strange a style,<br>Amaze th’ unlearn’d, and make the learned smile.<br>Unlucky, as Fungoso in the play,<br>These sparks with awkward vanity display<br>What the fine gentleman wore yesterday!<br>And but so mimic ancient wits at best,<br>As apes our grandsires, in their doublets dress’d.<br>In words, as fashions, the same rule will hold;<br>Alike fantastic, if too new, or old;<br>Be not the first by whom the new are tried,<br>Not yet the last to lay the old aside.</p><p>But most by numbers judge a poet’s song;<br>And smooth or rough, with them is right or wrong:<br>In the bright Muse though thousand charms conspire,<br>Her voice is all these tuneful fools admire,<br>Who haunt Parnassus but to please their ear,<br>Not mend their minds; as some to church repair,<br>Not for the doctrine, but the music there.<br>These equal syllables alone require,<br>Tho’ oft the ear the open vowels tire,<br>While expletives their feeble aid do join,<br><strong>And ten low words oft creep in one dull line,</strong><br><strong>While they ring round the same unvaried chimes,</strong><br><strong>With sure returns of still expected rhymes.</strong><br><strong>Where’er you find “the cooling western breeze”,</strong><br><strong>In the next line, it “whispers through the trees”:</strong><br><strong>If “crystal streams with pleasing murmurs creep”,</strong><br><strong>The reader’s threaten’d (not in vain) with “sleep”.</strong><br>Then, at the last and only couplet fraught<br>With some unmeaning thing they call a thought,<br>A needless Alexandrine ends the song,<br>That, like a wounded snake, drags its slow length along.<br>Leave such to tune their own dull rhymes, and know<br>What’s roundly smooth, or languishingly slow;<br>And praise the easy vigour of a line,<br>Where Denham’s strength, and Waller’s sweetness join.<br>True ease in writing comes from art, not chance,<br>As those move easiest who have learn’d to dance.<br>‘Tis not enough no harshness gives offence,<br>The sound must seem an echo to the sense.<br>Soft is the strain when Zephyr gently blows,<br>And the smooth stream in smoother numbers flows;<br>But when loud surges lash the sounding shore,<br>The hoarse, rough verse should like the torrent roar.<br>When Ajax strives some rock’s vast weight to throw,<br>The line too labours, and the words move slow;<br>Not so, when swift Camilla scours the plain,<br>Flies o’er th’ unbending corn, and skims along the main.<br>Hear how Timotheus’ varied lays surprise,<br>And bid alternate passions fall and rise!<br>While, at each change, the son of Libyan Jove<br>Now burns with glory, and then melts with love;<br>Now his fierce eyes with sparkling fury glow,<br>Now sighs steal out, and tears begin to flow:<br>Persians and Greeks like turns of nature found,<br>And the world’s victor stood subdu’d by sound!<br>The pow’r of music all our hearts allow,<br>And what Timotheus was, is Dryden now.</p><p>Avoid extremes; and shun the fault of such,<br>Who still are pleas’d too little or too much.<br>At ev’ry trifle scorn to take offence,<br>That always shows great pride, or little sense;<br>Those heads, as stomachs, are not sure the best,<br>Which nauseate all, and nothing can digest.<br>Yet let not each gay turn thy rapture move,<br>For fools admire, but men of sense approve;<br>As things seem large which we through mists descry,<br>Dulness is ever apt to magnify.</p><p>Some foreign writers, some our own despise;<br>The ancients only, or the moderns prize.<br>Thus wit, like faith, by each man is applied<br>To one small sect, and all are damn’d beside.<br>Meanly they seek the blessing to confine,<br>And force that sun but on a part to shine;<br>Which not alone the southern wit sublimes,<br>But ripens spirits in cold northern climes;<br>Which from the first has shone on ages past,<br>Enlights the present, and shall warm the last;<br>(Though each may feel increases and decays,<br>And see now clearer and now darker days.)<br>Regard not then if wit be old or new,<br>But blame the false, and value still the true.<br>Some ne’er advance a judgment of their own,<br>But catch the spreading notion of the town;<br>They reason and conclude by precedent,<br>And own stale nonsense which they ne’er invent.<br>Some judge of authors’ names, not works, and then<br>Nor praise nor blame the writings, but the men.<br>Of all this servile herd, the worst is he<br>That in proud dulness joins with quality,<br>A constant critic at the great man’s board,<br>To fetch and carry nonsense for my Lord.<br>What woeful stuff this madrigal would be,<br>In some starv’d hackney sonneteer, or me?<br>But let a Lord once own the happy lines,<br>How the wit brightens! how the style refines!<br>Before his sacred name flies every fault,<br>And each exalted stanza teems with thought!</p><p>The vulgar thus through imitation err;<br>As oft the learn’d by being singular;<br>So much they scorn the crowd, that if the throng<br>By chance go right, they purposely go wrong:<br>So Schismatics the plain believers quit,<br>And are but damn’d for having too much wit.</p><p>Some praise at morning what they blame at night;<br>But always think the last opinion right.<br>A Muse by these is like a mistress us’d,<br>This hour she’s idoliz’d, the next abus’d;<br>While their weak heads, like towns unfortified,<br>Twixt sense and nonsense daily change their side.<br>Ask them the cause; they’re wiser still, they say;<br>And still tomorrow’s wiser than today.<br>We think our fathers fools, so wise we grow;<br>Our wiser sons, no doubt, will think us so.<br>Once school divines this zealous isle o’erspread;<br>Who knew most Sentences, was deepest read;<br>Faith, Gospel, all, seem’d made to be disputed,<br>And none had sense enough to be confuted:<br>Scotists and Thomists, now, in peace remain,<br>Amidst their kindred cobwebs in Duck Lane.<br>If Faith itself has different dresses worn,<br>What wonder modes in wit should take their turn?<br>Oft, leaving what is natural and fit,<br>The current folly proves the ready wit;<br>And authors think their reputation safe<br>Which lives as long as fools are pleased to laugh.</p><p>Some valuing those of their own side or mind,<br>Still make themselves the measure of mankind;<br>Fondly we think we honour merit then,<br>When we but praise ourselves in other men.<br>Parties in wit attend on those of state,<br>And public faction doubles private hate.<br>Pride, Malice, Folly, against Dryden rose,<br>In various shapes of Parsons, Critics, Beaus;<br>But sense surviv’d, when merry jests were past;<br>For rising merit will buoy up at last.<br>Might he return, and bless once more our eyes,<br>New Blackmores and new Milbourns must arise;<br>Nay should great Homer lift his awful head,<br>Zoilus again would start up from the dead.<br>Envy will merit, as its shade, pursue,<br>But like a shadow, proves the substance true;<br>For envied wit, like Sol eclips’d, makes known<br>Th’ opposing body’s grossness, not its own.<br>When first that sun too powerful beams displays,<br>It draws up vapours which obscure its rays;<br>But ev’n those clouds at last adorn its way,<br>Reflect new glories, and augment the day.</p><p>Be thou the first true merit to befriend;<br>His praise is lost, who stays till all commend.<br>Short is the date, alas, of modern rhymes,<br>And ‘tis but just to let ‘em live betimes.<br>No longer now that golden age appears,<br>When patriarch wits surviv’d a thousand years:<br>Now length of Fame (our second life) is lost,<br>And bare threescore is all ev’n that can boast;<br>Our sons their fathers’ failing language see,<br>And such as Chaucer is, shall Dryden be.<br>So when the faithful pencil has design’d<br>Some bright idea of the master’s mind,<br>Where a new world leaps out at his command,<br>And ready Nature waits upon his hand;<br>When the ripe colours soften and unite,<br>And sweetly melt into just shade and light;<br>When mellowing years their full perfection give,<br>And each bold figure just begins to live,<br>The treacherous colours the fair art betray,<br>And all the bright creation fades away!</p><p>Unhappy wit, like most mistaken things,<br>Atones not for that envy which it brings.<br>In youth alone its empty praise we boast,<br>But soon the short-liv’d vanity is lost:<br>Like some fair flow’r the early spring supplies,<br>That gaily blooms, but ev’n in blooming dies.<br>What is this wit, which must our cares employ?<br>The owner’s wife, that other men enjoy;<br>Then most our trouble still when most admir’d,<br>And still the more we give, the more requir’d;<br>Whose fame with pains we guard, but lose with ease,<br>Sure some to vex, but never all to please;<br>‘Tis what the vicious fear, the virtuous shun;<br>By fools ‘tis hated, and by knaves undone!</p><p>If wit so much from ign’rance undergo,<br>Ah let not learning too commence its foe!<br>Of old, those met rewards who could excel,<br>And such were prais’d who but endeavour’d well:<br>Though triumphs were to gen’rals only due,<br>Crowns were reserv’d to grace the soldiers too.<br>Now, they who reach Parnassus’ lofty crown,<br>Employ their pains to spurn some others down;</p><p>And while self-love each jealous writer rules,<br>Contending wits become the sport of fools:<br>But still the worst with most regret commend,<br>For each ill author is as bad a friend.<br>To what base ends, and by what abject ways,<br>Are mortals urg’d through sacred lust of praise!<br>Ah ne’er so dire a thirst of glory boast,<br>Nor in the critic let the man be lost!<br>Good nature and good sense must ever join;</p><blockquote><p>To err is human; to forgive, divine.</p></blockquote><p>But if in noble minds some dregs remain,<br>Not yet purg’d off, of spleen and sour disdain,<br>Discharge that rage on more provoking crimes,<br>Nor fear a dearth in these flagitious times.<br>No pardon vile obscenity should find,<br>Though wit and art conspire to move your mind;<br>But dulness with obscenity must prove<br>As shameful sure as impotence in love.<br>In the fat age of pleasure, wealth, and ease,<br>Sprung the rank weed, and thriv’d with large increase:<br>When love was all an easy monarch’s care;<br>Seldom at council, never in a war:<br>Jilts ruled the state, and statesmen farces writ;<br>Nay wits had pensions, and young Lords had wit:<br>The fair sat panting at a courtier’s play,<br>And not a mask went unimprov’d away:<br>The modest fan was lifted up no more,<br>And virgins smil’d at what they blush’d before.<br>The following licence of a foreign reign<br>Did all the dregs of bold Socinus drain;<br>Then unbelieving priests reform’d the nation,<br>And taught more pleasant methods of salvation;<br>Where Heav’n’s free subjects might their rights dispute,<br>Lest God himself should seem too absolute:<br>Pulpits their sacred satire learned to spare,<br>And Vice admired to find a flatt’rer there!<br>Encourag’d thus, wit’s Titans brav’d the skies,<br>And the press groan’d with licenc’d blasphemies.<br>These monsters, critics! with your darts engage,<br>Here point your thunder, and exhaust your rage!<br>Yet shun their fault, who, scandalously nice,<br>Will needs mistake an author into vice;<br>All seems infected that th’ infected spy,<br>As all looks yellow to the jaundic’d eye.</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/44897/an-essay-on-criticism-part-2">An Essay on Criticism: Part 2</a></li><li>A little Learning is a dangerous thing 一知半解危害大，知之为知之，不知为不知</li><li>To err is human; to forgive, divine. 犯错是人，宽恕是神。</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope&quot;&gt;Alexander Pope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the causes which conspire to blind&lt;br&gt;Man’s er</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>An Essay on Criticism Part 1</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/28/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-1-Alexander-Pope/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/28/An-Essay-on-Criticism-Part-1-Alexander-Pope/</id>
    <published>2022-06-29T02:27:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-30T03:16:01.886Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope">Alexander Pope</a></p><p>Si quid novisti rectius istis,<br>Candidus imperti; si non, his utere mecum<br>&#91;If you have come to know any precept more correct than these, share it with me, brilliant one; if not, use these with me&#93; &#40;Horace, Epistle I.6.67&#41;</p><p>PART 1<br><strong>‘Tis hard to say, if greater want of skill</strong><br><strong>Appear in writing or in judging ill;</strong><br><strong>But, of the two, less dang’rous is th’ offence</strong><br><strong>To tire our patience, than mislead our sense.</strong><br><strong>Some few in that, but numbers err in this,</strong><br><strong>Ten censure wrong for one who writes amiss;</strong><br><strong>A fool might once himself alone expose,</strong><br><strong>Now one in verse makes many more in prose.</strong></p><p>‘Tis with our judgments as our watches, none<br>Go just alike, yet each believes his own.<br>In poets as true genius is but rare,<br>True taste as seldom is the critic’s share;<br>Both must alike from Heav’n derive their light,<br>These born to judge, as well as those to write.<br>Let such teach others who themselves excel,<br>And censure freely who have written well.<br>Authors are partial to their wit, ‘tis true,<br>But are not critics to their judgment too?</p><p>Yet if we look more closely we shall find<br>Most have the seeds of judgment in their mind;<br>Nature affords at least a glimm’ring light;<br>The lines, tho’ touch’d but faintly, are drawn right.<br>But as the slightest sketch, if justly trac’d,<br>Is by ill colouring but the more disgrac’d,<br>So by false learning is good sense defac’d;<br>Some are bewilder’d in the maze of schools,<br>And some made coxcombs Nature meant but fools.<br>In search of wit these lose their common sense,<br>And then turn critics in their own defence:<br>Each burns alike, who can, or cannot write,<br>Or with a rival’s, or an eunuch’s spite.<br>All fools have still an itching to deride,<br>And fain would be upon the laughing side.<br>If Mævius scribble in Apollo’s spite,<br>There are, who judge still worse than he can write.</p><p>Some have at first for wits, then poets pass’d,<br>Turn’d critics next, and prov’d plain fools at last;<br>Some neither can for wits nor critics pass,<br>As heavy mules are neither horse nor ass.<br>Those half-learn’d witlings, num’rous in our isle<br>As half-form’d insects on the banks of Nile;<br>Unfinish’d things, one knows not what to call,<br>Their generation’s so equivocal:<br>To tell ‘em, would a hundred tongues require,<br>Or one vain wit’s, that might a hundred tire.</p><p>But you who seek to give and merit fame,<br>And justly bear a critic’s noble name,<br>Be sure your self and your own reach to know,<br>How far your genius, taste, and learning go;<br>Launch not beyond your depth, but be discreet,<br>And mark that point where sense and dulness meet.</p><p>Nature to all things fix’d the limits fit,<br>And wisely curb’d proud man’s pretending wit:<br>As on the land while here the ocean gains,<br>In other parts it leaves wide sandy plains;<br>Thus in the soul while memory prevails,<br>The solid pow’r of understanding fails;<br>Where beams of warm imagination play,<br>The memory’s soft figures melt away.<br>One science only will one genius fit;<br>So vast is art, so narrow human wit:<br>Not only bounded to peculiar arts,<br>But oft in those, confin’d to single parts.<br>Like kings we lose the conquests gain’d before,<br>By vain ambition still to make them more;<br>Each might his sev’ral province well command,<br>Would all but stoop to what they understand.</p><p>First follow NATURE, and your judgment frame<br>By her just standard, which is still the same:<br>Unerring Nature, still divinely bright,<br>One clear, unchang’d, and universal light,<br>Life, force, and beauty, must to all impart,<br>At once the source, and end, and test of art.<br>Art from that fund each just supply provides,<br>Works without show, and without pomp presides:<br>In some fair body thus th’ informing soul<br>With spirits feeds, with vigour fills the whole,<br>Each motion guides, and ev’ry nerve sustains;<br>Itself unseen, but in th’ effects, remains.<br>Some, to whom Heav’n in wit has been profuse,<br>Want as much more, to turn it to its use;<br>For wit and judgment often are at strife,<br>Though meant each other’s aid, like man and wife.<br>‘Tis more to guide, than spur the Muse’s steed;<br>Restrain his fury, than provoke his speed;<br>The winged courser, like a gen’rous horse,<br>Shows most true mettle when you check his course.</p><p>Those RULES of old discover’d, not devis’d,<br>Are Nature still, but Nature methodis’d;<br>Nature, like liberty, is but restrain’d<br>By the same laws which first herself ordain’d.</p><p>Hear how learn’d Greece her useful rules indites,<br>When to repress, and when indulge our flights:<br>High on Parnassus’ top her sons she show’d,<br>And pointed out those arduous paths they trod;<br>Held from afar, aloft, th’ immortal prize,<br>And urg’d the rest by equal steps to rise.<br>Just precepts thus from great examples giv’n,<br>She drew from them what they deriv’d from Heav’n.<br>The gen’rous critic fann’d the poet’s fire,<br>And taught the world with reason to admire.<br>Then criticism the Muse’s handmaid prov’d,<br>To dress her charms, and make her more belov’d;<br>But following wits from that intention stray’d;<br>Who could not win the mistress, woo’d the maid;<br>Against the poets their own arms they turn’d,<br>Sure to hate most the men from whom they learn’d.<br>So modern ‘pothecaries, taught the art<br>By doctor’s bills to play the doctor’s part,<br>Bold in the practice of mistaken rules,<br>Prescribe, apply, and call their masters fools.<br>Some on the leaves of ancient authors prey,<br>Nor time nor moths e’er spoil’d so much as they:<br>Some drily plain, without invention’s aid,<br>Write dull receipts how poems may be made:<br>These leave the sense, their learning to display,<br>And those explain the meaning quite away.</p><p>You then whose judgment the right course would steer,<br>Know well each ANCIENT’S proper character;<br>His fable, subject, scope in ev’ry page;<br>Religion, country, genius of his age:<br>Without all these at once before your eyes,<br>Cavil you may, but never criticise.<br>Be Homer’s works your study and delight,<br>Read them by day, and meditate by night;<br>Thence form your judgment, thence your maxims bring,<br>And trace the Muses upward to their spring;<br>Still with itself compar’d, his text peruse;<br>And let your comment be the Mantuan Muse.</p><p>When first young Maro in his boundless mind<br>A work t’ outlast immortal Rome design’d,<br>Perhaps he seem’d above the critic’s law,<br>And but from Nature’s fountains scorn’d to draw:<br>But when t’ examine ev’ry part he came,<br>Nature and Homer were, he found, the same.<br>Convinc’d, amaz’d, he checks the bold design,<br>And rules as strict his labour’d work confine,<br>As if the Stagirite o’erlook’d each line.<br>Learn hence for ancient rules a just esteem;<br>To copy nature is to copy them.</p><p>Some beauties yet, no precepts can declare,<br>For there’s a happiness as well as care.<br>Music resembles poetry, in each<br>Are nameless graces which no methods teach,<br>And which a master-hand alone can reach.<br>If, where the rules not far enough extend,<br>(Since rules were made but to promote their end)<br>Some lucky LICENCE answers to the full<br>Th’ intent propos’d, that licence is a rule.<br>Thus Pegasus, a nearer way to take,<br>May boldly deviate from the common track.<br>Great wits sometimes may gloriously offend,<br>And rise to faults true critics dare not mend;<br>From vulgar bounds with brave disorder part,<br>And snatch a grace beyond the reach of art,<br>Which, without passing through the judgment, gains<br>The heart, and all its end at once attains.<br>In prospects, thus, some objects please our eyes,<br>Which out of nature’s common order rise,<br>The shapeless rock, or hanging precipice.<br>But tho’ the ancients thus their rules invade,<br>(As kings dispense with laws themselves have made)<br>Moderns, beware! or if you must offend<br>Against the precept, ne’er transgress its end;<br>Let it be seldom, and compell’d by need,<br>And have, at least, their precedent to plead.<br>The critic else proceeds without remorse,<br>Seizes your fame, and puts his laws in force.</p><p>I know there are, to whose presumptuous thoughts<br>Those freer beauties, ev’n in them, seem faults.<br>Some figures monstrous and misshap’d appear,<br>Consider’d singly, or beheld too near,<br>Which, but proportion’d to their light, or place,<br>Due distance reconciles to form and grace.<br>A prudent chief not always must display<br>His pow’rs in equal ranks, and fair array,<br>But with th’ occasion and the place comply,<br>Conceal his force, nay seem sometimes to fly.<br>Those oft are stratagems which errors seem,<br>Nor is it Homer nods, but we that dream.</p><p>Still green with bays each ancient altar stands,<br>Above the reach of sacrilegious hands,<br>Secure from flames, from envy’s fiercer rage,<br>Destructive war, and all-involving age.<br>See, from each clime the learn’d their incense bring!<br>Hear, in all tongues consenting pæans ring!<br>In praise so just let ev’ry voice be join’d,<br>And fill the gen’ral chorus of mankind!<br>Hail, bards triumphant! born in happier days;<br>Immortal heirs of universal praise!<br>Whose honours with increase of ages grow,<br>As streams roll down, enlarging as they flow!<br>Nations unborn your mighty names shall sound,<br>And worlds applaud that must not yet be found!<br>Oh may some spark of your celestial fire<br>The last, the meanest of your sons inspire,<br>(That on weak wings, from far, pursues your flights;<br>Glows while he reads, but trembles as he writes)<br>To teach vain wits a science little known,<br>T’ admire superior sense, and doubt their own! </p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/44896/an-essay-on-criticism-part-1">An Essay on Criticism: Part 1</a></li><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Essay_on_Criticism">An Essay on Criticism</a></li><li>Alexander Pope 并非亚历山大教皇 &#40;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pope_Alexander">Pope Alexander</a>&#41;</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Pope&quot;&gt;Alexander Pope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si quid novisti rectius istis,&lt;br&gt;Candidus imperti; s</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Question</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/24/a-question-robert-frost/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/24/a-question-robert-frost/</id>
    <published>2022-06-24T23:47:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-25T11:55:18.391Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Frost">Robert Frost</a></p><p>A voice said, Look me in the stars<br>And tell me truly, men of earth,<br>If all the soul-and-body scars<br>Were not too much to pay for birth.</p><hr><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Question_%28poem%29">A Question &#40;poem&#41;</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Frost&quot;&gt;Robert Frost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A voice said, Look me in the stars&lt;br&gt;And tell me truly, </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Life That I Have</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/23/the-life-that-i-have-leo-marks/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/23/the-life-that-i-have-leo-marks/</id>
    <published>2022-06-24T02:42:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-24T02:45:30.698Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Marks">Leo Marks</a></p><p>The life that I have<br>Is all that I have<br>And the life that I have<br>Is yours.</p><p>The love that I have<br>Of the life that I have<br>Is yours and yours and yours.</p><p>A sleep I shall have<br>A rest I shall have<br>Yet death will be but a pause.</p><p>For the peace of my years<br>In the long green grass<br>Will be yours and yours and yours.</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Life_That_I_Have">The Life That I Have</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Marks&quot;&gt;Leo Marks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The life that I have&lt;br&gt;Is all that I have&lt;br&gt;And the life that</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Computational Thinking</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/05/computational-thinking-jeannette-wing/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/05/computational-thinking-jeannette-wing/</id>
    <published>2022-06-05T18:35:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-21T02:50:13.518Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeannette_Wing">Jeannette Wing</a></p><blockquote><p>It represents a universally applicable attitude and skill set everyone, not just computer scientists, would be eager to learn and use.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Computational thinking</strong> builds on the power and limits of computing processes, whether they are executed by a human or by a machine. Computational methods and models give us the courage to solve problems and design systems that no one of us would be capable of tackling alone. Computational thinking confronts the riddle of machine intelligence: What can humans do better than computers? and<br>What can computers do better than humans? Most fundamentally it addresses the question: What is computable? Today, we know only parts of the answers to such questions.</p><p><strong>Computational thinking</strong> is a fundamental skill for everyone, not just for computer scientists. To reading, writing, and arithmetic, we should add computational thinking to every child’s analytical ability. Just as the printing press facilitated the spread of the three Rs, what is appropriately incestuous about this vision is that computing and computers facilitate the spread of computational thinking.</p><p>Computational thinking involves <strong>solving problems, designing systems, and understanding human behavior, by drawing on the concepts fundamental to computer science</strong>. Computational thinking includes a range of mental tools that reflect the breadth of the field of computer science.</p><p>Having to solve a particular problem, we might ask: How difficult is it to solve? and What’s the best way to solve it? Computer science rests on solid theoretical underpinnings to answer such questions precisely. Stating the difficulty of a problem accounts for the underlying power of the machine—the computing device that will run the solution. We must consider the machine’s instruction set, its resource constraints, and its operating environment.</p><p>In solving a problem efficiently, we might further ask whether an approximate solution is good<br>enough, whether we can use randomization to our advantage, and whether false positives or false negatives are allowed. Computational thinking is reformulating a seemingly difficult problem into one we know how to solve, perhaps by reduction, embedding, transformation, or simulation.</p><p>Computational thinking is thinking recursively. It is parallel processing. It is interpreting code as data and data as code. It is type checking as the generalization of dimensional analysis. It is recognizing both the virtues and the dangers of aliasing, or giving someone or something more than one name. It is recognizing both the cost and power of indirect addressing and procedure call. It is judging a program not just for correctness and efficiency but for aesthetics, and a system’s design for simplicity and elegance.</p><p>Computational thinking is using abstraction and decomposition when attacking a large complex task<br>or designing a large complex system. It is separation of concerns. It is choosing an appropriate representation for a problem or modeling the relevant aspects of a problem to make it tractable. It is using invariants to describe a system’s behavior succinctly and declaratively. It is having the confidence we can safely use, modify, and influence a large complex system without understanding its every detail. It is modularizing something in anticipation of multiple users or prefetching and caching in anticipation of future use.</p><blockquote><p>Thinking like a computer scientist means more than being able to program a computer. It requires thinking at multiple levels of abstraction.</p></blockquote><p>Computational thinking is thinking in terms of prevention, protection, and recovery from worst-case<br>scenarios through redundancy, damage containment, and error correction. It is calling gridlock deadlock and contracts interfaces. It is learning to avoid race conditions when synchronizing meetings with one another.</p><p>Computational thinking is using heuristic reasoning to discover a solution. It is planning, learning, and scheduling in the presence of uncertainty. It is search, search, and more search, resulting in a list of Web pages, a strategy for winning a game, or a counterexample. Computational thinking is using massive amounts of data to speed up computation. It is making trade-offs between time and space and between processing power and storage capacity.</p><p>Consider these everyday examples: When your daughter goes to school in the morning, she puts in her backpack the things she needs for the day; that’s prefetching and caching. When your son loses his<br>mittens, you suggest he retrace his steps; that’s backtracking. At what point do you stop renting skis and buy yourself a pair?; that’s online algorithms. Which line do you stand in at the supermarket?; that’s performance modeling for multi-server systems. Why does your telephone still work during a power outage?; that’s independence of failure and redundancy in design. How do Completely Automated Public Turing Test(s) to Tell Computers and Humans Apart, or CAPTCHAs, authenticate humans?; that’s exploiting the difficulty of solving hard AI problems to foil computing agents.</p><p>Computational thinking will have become ingrained in everyone’s lives when words like algorithm and precondition are part of everyone’s vocabulary; when nondeterminism and garbage collection take on the meanings used by computer scientists; and when trees are drawn upside down.</p><p>We have witnessed the influence of computational thinking on other disciplines. For example, machine learning has transformed statistics. Statistical learning is being used for problems on a scale, in terms of both data size and dimension, unimaginable only a few years ago. Statistics departments in all kinds of organizations are hiring computer scientists. Schools of computer science are embracing existing or starting up new statistics departments.</p><p>Computer scientists’recent interest in biology is driven by their belief that biologists can benefit from computational thinking. Computer science’s contribution to biology goes beyond the ability to search through vast amounts of sequence data looking for patterns. The hope is that data structures and algorithms—our computational abstractions and methods—can represent the structure of proteins in ways that elucidate their function. Computational biology is changing the way biologists<br>think. Similarly, computational game theory is changing the way economists think; nanocomputing, the way chemists think; and quantum computing, the way physicists think.</p><p>This kind of thinking will be part of the skill set of not only other scientists but of everyone else. Ubiquitous computing is to today as computational thinking is to tomorrow. Ubiquitous computing was yesterday’s dream that became today’s reality; computational thinking is tomorrow’s reality.</p><h1 id="WHAT-IT-IS-AND-ISN’T"><a href="#WHAT-IT-IS-AND-ISN’T" class="headerlink" title="WHAT IT IS, AND ISN’T"></a>WHAT IT IS, AND ISN’T</h1><p>Computer science is the study of computation — what can be computed and how to compute it. Computational thinking thus has the following characteristics:</p><p><em>Conceptualizing, not programming.</em> Computer science is not computer programming. Thinking like a computer scientist means more than being able to program a computer. It requires thinking at multiple levels of abstraction;</p><p><em>Fundamental, not rote skill.</em> A fundamental skill is something every human being must know to function in modern society. Rote means a mechanical routine. Ironically, not until computer science solves the AI Grand Challenge of making computers think like humans will thinking be rote;</p><p><em>A way that humans, not computers, think.</em> Computational thinking is a way humans solve problems; it is not trying to get humans to think like computers. Computers are dull and boring; humans are clever and imaginative. We humans make computers exciting. Equipped with computing devices, we use our cleverness to tackle problems we would not dare take on before the age of computing and build systems with functionality limited only by our imaginations;</p><p><em>Complements and combines mathematical and engineering thinking.</em> Computer science inherently draws on mathematical thinking, given that, like all sciences, its formal foundations rest on mathematics.<br>Computer science inherently draws on engineering thinking, given that we build systems that interact with the real world. The constraints of the underlying computing device force computer scientists to think computationally, not just mathematically. Being free to build virtual worlds<br>enables us to engineer systems beyond the physical world;</p><p><em>Ideas, not artifacts.</em> It’s not just the software and hardware artifacts we produce that will be physically present everywhere and touch our lives all the time, it will be the computational concepts we use to approach and solve problems, manage our daily lives, and communicate and interact<br>with other people; and</p><p><em>For everyone, everywhere.</em> Computational thinking will be a reality when it is so integral to human<br>endeavors it disappears as an explicit philosophy.</p><p>Many people equate computer science with computer programming. Some parents see only a narrow range of job opportunities for their children who major in computer science. Many people think the fundamental research in computer science is done and that only the engineering remains. Computational thinking is a grand vision to guide computer science educators, researchers, and practitioners as we act to change society’s image of the field. We especially need to reach the pre-college audience, including teachers, parents, and students, sending them two main messages:</p><p><em>Intellectually challenging and engaging scientific problems remain to be understood and solved.</em> The problem domain and solution domain are limited only by our own curiosity and creativity; and One can major in computer science and do anything. One can major in English or mathematics and go on to a multitude of different careers. Ditto computer science. One can major in computer science and go on to a career in medicine, law, business, politics, any type of science or engineering, and even the arts.</p><p>Professors of computer science should teach a course called “Ways to Think Like a Computer Scientist” to college freshmen, making it available to non-majors, not just to computer science majors. We should expose pre-college students to computational methods and models. Rather than bemoan the decline of interest in computer science or the decline in funding for research in computer science, we should look to inspire the public’s interest in the intellectual adventure of the field. We’ll thus spread the joy, awe, and power of computer science, aiming to make computational thinking commonplace.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeannette_Wing&quot;&gt;Jeannette Wing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It represents a universally applicable a</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="programmer" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/programmer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Star</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/01/the-star-jane-taylor/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/01/the-star-jane-taylor/</id>
    <published>2022-06-02T03:59:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-02T04:07:16.492Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_Taylor_%28poet%29">Jane Taylor</a></p><p>Twinkle, twinkle, little star,<br>How I wonder what you are!<br>Up above the world so high,<br>Like a diamond in the sky.</p><p>When the blazing sun is gone,<br>When he nothing shines upon,<br>Then you show your little light,<br>Twinkle, twinkle, all the night.</p><p>Then the trav’ller in the dark,<br>Thanks you for your tiny spark,<br>He could not see which way to go,<br>If you did not twinkle so.</p><p>In the dark blue sky you keep,<br>And often thro’ my curtains peep,<br>For you never shut your eye,<br>Till the sun is in the sky.</p><p>‘Tis your bright and tiny spark,<br>Lights the trav’ller in the dark,<br>Tho’ I know not what you are,<br>Twinkle, twinkle, little star. </p><iframe style="border-radius:12px" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/3N6kzbnfpTPB5J9NAGc1rU?utm_source=generator" width="300" height="380" frameBorder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"></iframe><hr><ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twinkle,_Twinkle,_Little_Star">Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star</a></li><li><a href="https://poets.org/poem/star">The Star</a></li><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/45316/the-star-56d224c697fbe">The Star</a></li><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/43200/twinkle-twinkle-little-star">Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_Taylor_%28poet%29&quot;&gt;Jane Taylor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twinkle, twinkle, little star,&lt;br&gt;How I wonder w</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My English Words List - June - 2022</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/01/my-english-words-list-june-2022/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/06/01/my-english-words-list-june-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-06-01T16:50:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-27T16:51:32.905Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="walkathon"><a href="#walkathon" class="headerlink" title="walkathon"></a>walkathon</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/walkathon">walkathon</a></p><h2 id="noun"><a href="#noun" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><ul><li>a walk covering a considerable distance organized especially to raise money for a cause</li></ul><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fe/The_children_playing_the_Band_on_the_occasion_of_International_Day_of_Older_Persons_at_a_Intergenerational_Walkathon_of_the_Senior_Citizens_in_New_Delhi_on_October_01%2C_2006.jpg/440px-thumbnail.jpg" alt="The children playing the Band on the occasion of International Day of Older Persons at a Intergenerational Walkathon of the Senior Citizens in New Delhi on October 01, 2006"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walkathon">Walkathon</a></p><h1 id="pledge"><a href="#pledge" class="headerlink" title="pledge"></a>pledge</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/pledge">pledge</a></p><h2 id="noun-1"><a href="#noun-1" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>To make a pledge or donation, please call the charity’s office. </p><h1 id="breakdown"><a href="#breakdown" class="headerlink" title="breakdown"></a>breakdown</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/breakdown">breakdown</a></p><h2 id="noun-2"><a href="#noun-2" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>the breakdown of water into hydrogen and oxygen</p><p>a budget breakdown</p><h1 id="ellipse"><a href="#ellipse" class="headerlink" title="ellipse"></a>ellipse</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/ellipse">ellipse</a></p><h2 id="noun-3"><a href="#noun-3" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5f/Ellipse-conic.svg/440px-Ellipse-conic.svg.png" alt="An ellipse (red) obtained as the intersection of a cone with an inclined plane."></p><ul><li>oval</li><li>a shape that looks like a flattened circle</li></ul><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ellipse">Ellipse</a></p><h1 id="genre"><a href="#genre" class="headerlink" title="genre"></a>genre</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/genre">genre</a></p><h2 id="noun-4"><a href="#noun-4" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>This book is a classic of the mystery genre.</p><h1 id="mend"><a href="#mend" class="headerlink" title="mend"></a>mend</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/mend">mend</a></p><h2 id="verb"><a href="#verb" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><p>The town needs to mend these roads.</p><p>It’s never too late to mend.</p><h1 id="criterion"><a href="#criterion" class="headerlink" title="criterion"></a>criterion</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/criterion">criterion</a></p><h2 id="noun-5"><a href="#noun-5" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>the university’s criteria for admission</p><h1 id="moderator"><a href="#moderator" class="headerlink" title="moderator"></a>moderator</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/moderator">moderator</a></p><h2 id="noun-6"><a href="#noun-6" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>The moderator allowed audience members to ask the governor questions. </p><p>She acts as the moderator in our office meetings.</p><h1 id="vend"><a href="#vend" class="headerlink" title="vend"></a>vend</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/vend">vend</a></p><h2 id="verb-1"><a href="#verb-1" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><p>vends snack foods and novelties at fairs</p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3a/HK_Sunday_night_West_Kln_Promenade_Food_Vending_Machine_%E5%B0%8F%E9%A3%9F_01.JPG/340px-HK_Sunday_night_West_Kln_Promenade_Food_Vending_Machine_%E5%B0%8F%E9%A3%9F_01.JPG" alt="A snack food vending machine in Hong Kong"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vending_machine">Vending machine</a></p><h1 id="vendor"><a href="#vendor" class="headerlink" title="vendor"></a>vendor</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/vendor">vendor</a></p><h2 id="noun-7"><a href="#noun-7" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>we’re thinking of making a deal with that other software vendor</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vendor">Vendor</a></p><h1 id="dispense"><a href="#dispense" class="headerlink" title="dispense"></a>dispense</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/dispense">dispense</a></p><h2 id="verb-2"><a href="#verb-2" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><p>dispense food among the needy</p><p>The ATM only dispenses $20 bills.</p><p>dispensing pills to their patients</p><p>Pharmacists are certified to dispense medication.</p><h1 id="rim"><a href="#rim" class="headerlink" title="rim"></a>rim</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/rim">rim</a></p><h2 id="noun-8"><a href="#noun-8" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>He bought stainless steel rims for his new car. </p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5f/Scratched_rim_on_one-piece_wheel.jpg/440px-Scratched_rim_on_one-piece_wheel.jpg" alt="Scratched rim on a one-piece alloy wheel. The black residue remains from where the tire was seated on the &quot;safety profile&quot; rim."></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rim_%28wheel%29">Rim &#40;wheel&#41;</a></p><h1 id="precaution"><a href="#precaution" class="headerlink" title="precaution"></a>precaution</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/precaution">precaution</a></p><h2 id="noun-9"><a href="#noun-9" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>When driving, she always wears her seatbelt as a precaution. </p><p>Every home owner should take precautions against fire.</p><h1 id="wrestling"><a href="#wrestling" class="headerlink" title="wrestling"></a>wrestling</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/wrestling">wrestling</a></p><h2 id="noun-10"><a href="#noun-10" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>My favorite sport is wrestling.</p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cf/Two_people_arm_wrestling.jpg/440px-Two_people_arm_wrestling.jpg" alt="Arm Wrestling"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arm_wrestling">Arm wrestling</a></p><h1 id="juggle"><a href="#juggle" class="headerlink" title="juggle"></a>juggle</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/juggle">juggle</a></p><h2 id="verb-3"><a href="#verb-3" class="headerlink" title="verb"></a>verb</h2><p>He juggled four balls at once. </p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/77/Afghan_circus.jpg/440px-Afghan_circus.jpg" alt="Children performing juggling as part of the International Jugglers&#39; Association supported Mobile Mini Circus for Children"></p><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/ad/Man_juggles_ball.jpg/340px-Man_juggles_ball.jpg" alt="Juggling a soccer ball"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juggling">Juggling</a></p><h1 id="alias"><a href="#alias" class="headerlink" title="alias"></a>alias</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/aliases">alias</a></p><h2 id="noun-11"><a href="#noun-11" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>He checked into the hotel using an alias.</p><h1 id="breach"><a href="#breach" class="headerlink" title="breach"></a>breach</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/breach">breach</a></p><h2 id="noun-12"><a href="#noun-12" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>Many people consider her decision to be a breach of trust.</p><h1 id="escort"><a href="#escort" class="headerlink" title="escort"></a>escort</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/escort">escort</a></p><h2 id="noun-13"><a href="#noun-13" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>Everyone was surprised when she arrived at the party without an escort.</p><h1 id="linen"><a href="#linen" class="headerlink" title="linen"></a>linen</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/linen">linen</a></p><h2 id="noun-14"><a href="#noun-14" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2c/Handkerchief.jpg/500px-Handkerchief.jpg" alt="A linen handkerchief with drawn thread work around the edges"></p><ul><li>clothing or household articles made of linen cloth or similar fabric</li><li>household articles (as tablecloths or sheets) or clothing that were once often made of linen</li></ul><p>She washes the linen every week.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linen">Linen</a></p><h1 id="orangutan"><a href="#orangutan" class="headerlink" title="orangutan"></a>orangutan</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/orangutan">orangutan</a></p><h2 id="noun-15"><a href="#noun-15" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/be/Orang_Utan%2C_Semenggok_Forest_Reserve%2C_Sarawak%2C_Borneo%2C_Malaysia.JPG/440px-Orang_Utan%2C_Semenggok_Forest_Reserve%2C_Sarawak%2C_Borneo%2C_Malaysia.JPG" alt="Bornean orangutan"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orangutan">Orangutan</a></p><h1 id="desperate"><a href="#desperate" class="headerlink" title="desperate"></a>desperate</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/desperate">desperate</a></p><h2 id="adjective"><a href="#adjective" class="headerlink" title="adjective"></a>adjective</h2><p>The collapse of her business had made her desperate. </p><p>As the supply of food ran out, people became desperate. </p><p>We could hear their desperate cries for help. </p><p>a desperate struggle to defeat the enemy</p><h1 id="aggregate"><a href="#aggregate" class="headerlink" title="aggregate"></a>aggregate</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/aggregate">aggregate</a></p><h2 id="adjective-1"><a href="#adjective-1" class="headerlink" title="adjective"></a>adjective</h2><p>aggregate sales</p><p>An aggregate function performs a calculation on a set of values, and returns a single value.</p><p>Aggregate functions are often used with the GROUP BY clause of the SELECT statement.</p><h1 id="novice"><a href="#novice" class="headerlink" title="novice"></a>novice</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/novice">novice</a></p><h2 id="noun-16"><a href="#noun-16" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p>a novice at skiing</p><h1 id="jersey"><a href="#jersey" class="headerlink" title="jersey"></a>jersey</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/jersey">jersey</a></p><h2 id="noun-17"><a href="#noun-17" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><ul><li>a shirt made of knitted fabric and especially one worn by a sports team</li></ul><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d1/Tour_de_France_2006_yellow_jersey_%28Floyd_Landis%29.jpg/440px-Tour_de_France_2006_yellow_jersey_%28Floyd_Landis%29.jpg" alt="A modern cycling jersey"></p><p>a football jersey</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jersey_%28clothing%29">Jersey &#40;clothing&#41;</a></p><h1 id="castanet"><a href="#castanet" class="headerlink" title="castanet"></a>castanet</h1><p><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/castanet">castanet</a></p><h2 id="noun-18"><a href="#noun-18" class="headerlink" title="noun"></a>noun</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a5/Castagnetten.jpg/299px-Castagnetten.jpg" alt="Castanets"></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castanets">Castanets</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;walkathon&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#walkathon&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;walkathon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;walkathon&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/d</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="ELL" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/ELL/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Warm Summer Sun</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/31/warm-summer-sun-mark-twain/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/31/warm-summer-sun-mark-twain/</id>
    <published>2022-05-31T21:57:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-31T22:03:42.220Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Twain">Mark Twain</a></p><p>Warm summer sun,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Shine kindly here,<br>Warm southern wind,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Blow softly here.<br>Green sod above,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Lie light, lie light.<br>Good night, dear heart,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Good night, good night.</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/46037/warm-summer-sun">Warm Summer Sun</a></li><li><a href="https://poets.org/poem/warm-summer-sun">Warm Summer Sun</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Twain&quot;&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm summer sun,&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Shine kindly here,&lt;br&gt;Warm so</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thanatopsis</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/21/thanatopsis-william-cullen-bryant/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/21/thanatopsis-william-cullen-bryant/</id>
    <published>2022-05-22T03:08:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-22T03:14:02.440Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Cullen_Bryant">William Cullen Bryant</a></p><p>To him who in the love of Nature holds<br>Communion with her visible forms, she speaks<br>A various language; for his gayer hours<br>She has a voice of gladness, and a smile<br>And eloquence of beauty, and she glides<br>Into his darker musings, with a mild<br>And healing sympathy, that steals away<br>Their sharpness, ere he is aware. When thoughts<br>Of the last bitter hour come like a blight<br>Over thy spirit, and sad images<br>Of the stern agony, and shroud, and pall,<br>And breathless darkness, and the narrow house,<br>Make thee to shudder, and grow sick at heart;—<br>Go forth, under the open sky, and list<br>To Nature’s teachings, while from all around—<br>Earth and her waters, and the depths of air—<br>Comes a still voice—<br>Yet a few days, and thee<br>The all-beholding sun shall see no more<br>In all his course; nor yet in the cold ground,<br>Where thy pale form was laid, with many tears,<br>Nor in the embrace of ocean, shall exist<br>Thy image. Earth, that nourished thee, shall claim<br>Thy growth, to be resolved to earth again,<br>And, lost each human trace, surrendering up<br>Thine individual being, shalt thou go<br>To mix for ever with the elements,<br>To be a brother to the insensible rock<br>And to the sluggish clod, which the rude swain<br>Turns with his share, and treads upon. The oak<br>Shall send his roots abroad, and pierce thy mould.</p><p>Yet not to thine eternal resting-place<br>Shalt thou retire alone, nor couldst thou wish<br>Couch more magnificent. Thou shalt lie down<br>With patriarchs of the infant world—with kings,<br>The powerful of the earth—the wise, the good,<br>Fair forms, and hoary seers of ages past,<br>All in one mighty sepulchre.   The hills<br>Rock-ribbed and ancient as the sun,—the vales<br>Stretching in pensive quietness between;<br>The venerable woods—rivers that move<br>In majesty, and the complaining brooks<br>That make the meadows green; and, poured round all,<br>Old Ocean’s gray and melancholy waste,—<br>Are but the solemn decorations all<br>Of the great tomb of man. The golden sun,<br>The planets, all the infinite host of heaven,<br>Are shining on the sad abodes of death,<br>Through the still lapse of ages. All that tread<br>The globe are but a handful to the tribes<br>That slumber in its bosom.—Take the wings<br>Of morning, pierce the Barcan wilderness,<br>Or lose thyself in the continuous woods<br>Where rolls the Oregon, and hears no sound,<br>Save his own dashings—yet the dead are there:<br>And millions in those solitudes, since first<br>The flight of years began, have laid them down<br>In their last sleep—the dead reign there alone.</p><p>So shalt thou rest, and what if thou withdraw<br>In silence from the living, and no friend<br>Take note of thy departure? All that breathe<br>Will share thy destiny. The gay will laugh<br>When thou art gone, the solemn brood of care<br>Plod on, and each one as before will chase<br>His favorite phantom; yet all these shall leave<br>Their mirth and their employments, and shall come<br>And make their bed with thee. As the long train<br>Of ages glide away, the sons of men,<br>The youth in life’s green spring, and he who goes<br>In the full strength of years, matron and maid,<br>The speechless babe, and the gray-headed man—<br>Shall one by one be gathered to thy side,<br>By those, who in their turn shall follow them.<br>So live, that when thy summons comes to join<br>The innumerable caravan, which moves<br>To that mysterious realm, where each shall take<br>His chamber in the silent halls of death,<br>Thou go not, like the quarry-slave at night,<br>Scourged to his dungeon, but, sustained and soothed<br>By an unfaltering trust, approach thy grave,<br>Like one who wraps the drapery of his couch<br>About him, and lies down to pleasant dreams.</p><hr><ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanatopsis">Thanatopsis</a></li><li><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/50465/thanatopsis">Thanatopsis</a></li><li><a href="https://poets.org/poem/thanatopsis">Thanatopsis</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Cullen_Bryant&quot;&gt;William Cullen Bryant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To him who in the love of Nature holds&lt;</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Work</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/20/work-eliza-cook/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/20/work-eliza-cook/</id>
    <published>2022-05-21T03:18:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-21T03:22:33.790Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eliza_Cook">Eliza Cook</a></p><p>Work, work, my boy, be not afraid;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Look labor boldly in the face;<br>Take up the hammer or the spade,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;And blush not for your humble place.</p><p>There’s glory in the shuttle’s song;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;There’s triumph in the anvil’s stroke;<br>There’s merit in the brave and strong<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Who dig the mine or fell the oak.</p><p>The wind disturbs the sleeping lake,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;And bids it ripple pure and fresh;<br>It moves the green boughs till they make<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Grand music in their leafy mesh.</p><p>And so the active breath of life<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Should stir our dull and sluggard wills;<br>For are we not created rife<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;With health, that stagnant torpor kills?</p><p>I doubt if he who lolls his head<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;Where idleness and plenty meet,<br>Enjoys his pillow or his bread<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;As those who earn the meals they eat.</p><p>And man is never half so blest<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;As when the busy day is spent<br>So as to make his evening rest<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;A holiday of glad content.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eliza_Cook&quot;&gt;Eliza Cook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work, work, my boy, be not afraid;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Look labor </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Birds In Summer</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/19/birds-in-summer-mary-howitt/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/19/birds-in-summer-mary-howitt/</id>
    <published>2022-05-20T03:27:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-20T03:39:19.591Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Howitt">Mary Howitt</a></p><p>How pleasant the life of a bird must be,<br>Flitting about in each leafy tree:<br>In the leafy trees so broad and tall,<br>Like a green and beautiful palace-hall<br>With its airy chambers light and boon,<br>That open to sun, and stars, and moon!<br>That open unto the bright blue sky.<br>And the frolicsome winds as they wander by.</p><p>They have left their nests in the forest bough;<br>Those homes of delight they need not now;<br>And the young and the old they wander out<br>And traverse their green world round about;<br>And hark! at the top of this leafy hall,<br>How one to the other they lovingly call:<br>“Come up, come up!” they seem to say,<br>“Where the topmost twigs in the breezes sway!”</p><p>“Come up, come up, for the world is fair<br>Where the merry leaves dance in the summer air,”<br>And the birds below give back the cry:<br>“We come, we come, to the branches high!”<br>How pleasant the life of a bird must be<br>Flitting about in a leafy tree;<br>And away through the air what joy to go,<br>And to look on the bright green earth below.</p><p>How pleasant the life of a bird must be,<br>Wherever it listeth there to flee;<br>To go, when a joyful fancy calls,<br>Dashing adown ‘mong the waterfalls,<br>Then wheeling about with its mates at play,<br>Above and below, and among the spray,<br>Hither and thither, with screams as wild<br>As the laughing mirth of a rosy child!</p><p>How pleasant the life of a bird must be,<br>Skimming about on the breezy sea,<br>Cresting the billows like silvery foam,<br>And then wheeling away to its cliff-built home<br>What joy it must be to sail, upborne<br>By a strong free wing, through the rosy morn,<br>To meet the young sun face to face,<br>And pierce like a shaft the boundless space!</p><p>What joy it must be, like a living breeze,<br>To flutter about ‘mong the flowering trees;<br>Lightly to soar and to see beneath<br>The wastes of the blossoming purple heath,<br>And the yellow furze like fields of gold<br>That gladden some fairy regions old!<br>On mountain tops, on the billowy sea,<br>On the leafy stems of the forest tree,<br>How pleasant the life of a bird must be!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Howitt&quot;&gt;Mary Howitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How pleasant the life of a bird must be,&lt;br&gt;Flitting about </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Voice Of Spring</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/19/the-voice-of-spring-mary-howitt/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/19/the-voice-of-spring-mary-howitt/</id>
    <published>2022-05-20T03:16:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-20T03:26:13.507Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Howitt">Mary Howitt</a></p><p>I am coming, little maiden!<br>With the pleasant sunshine laden,<br>With the honey for the bee,<br>With the blossom for the tree,<br>With the flower and with the leaf:—<br>Till I come, the time is brief.</p><p>I am coming, I am coming!<br>Hark! the little bee is humming;<br>See! the lark is soaring<br>high In the bright and sunny sky;<br>And the gnats(4) are on the wing.<br>Wheeling round in airy ring. </p><p>See! the yellow catkins cover<br>All the slender willows over;<br>And on banks of mossy green<br>Star-like primroses are seen;<br>And, their clustering leaves below<br>White and purple violets blow. </p><p>Hark! the new-born lambs are bleating;<br>And the cawing rooks are meeting<br>In the elms—a noisy crowd!<br>All the birds are singing loud;<br>And the first white butterfly<br>In the sunshine dances by. </p><p>Look around thee—look around!<br>Flowers in all the fields abound;<br>Every running stream is bright;<br>All the orchard(8) trees are white,<br>And each small and waving shoot<br>Promises sweet flowers and fruit. </p><p>Turn thine eyes to earth and heaven!<br>God for thee the Spring has given;<br>Taught the birds their melodies,<br>Clothed the earth, and cleared the skies,<br>For thy pleasure or thy food:—<br>Pour thy soul in gratitude?</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Howitt&quot;&gt;Mary Howitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am coming, little maiden!&lt;br&gt;With the pleasant sunshine l</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Great, Wide, Beautiful, Wonderful World</title>
    <link href="https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/18/great-wide-beautiful-wonderful-world-william-brighty-rands/"/>
    <id>https://hezhigang.github.io/2022/05/18/great-wide-beautiful-wonderful-world-william-brighty-rands/</id>
    <published>2022-05-19T01:13:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-19T01:41:16.988Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Brighty_Rands">William Brighty Rands</a></p><p>Great, wide, beautiful, wonderful World,<br>With the wonderful water round you curled,<br>And the wonderful grass upon your breast–<br>World, you are beautifully drest.</p><p>The wonderful air is over me,<br>And the wonderful wind is shaking the tree,<br>It walks on the water, and whirls the mills,<br>And talks to itself on the tops of the hills.</p><p>You friendly Earth! how far do you go,<br>With the wheat-fields that nod and the rivers that flow,<br>With cities and gardens, and cliffs, and isles,<br>And people upon you for thousands of miles?</p><p>Ah, you are so great, and I am so small,<br>I tremble to think of you, World, at all;<br>And yet, when I said my prayers to-day,<br>A whisper inside me seemed to say,<br>“You are more than the Earth, though you are such a dot:<br>You can love and think, and the Earth cannot!”</p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3IJ8Ch2ba44" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><hr><ul><li><a href="https://rpo.library.utoronto.ca/content/great-wide-beautiful-wonderful-world">Great, Wide, Beautiful, Wonderful World</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Brighty_Rands&quot;&gt;William Brighty Rands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, wide, beautiful, wonderful World</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="english" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/english/"/>
    
    <category term="poem" scheme="https://hezhigang.github.io/tags/poem/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
